FRANCISCO GERARDO ESPINO SANDOVAL

Mobile: 425-247-9965 gerardo97 sandoval@hotmail.com

Summary:

Bachelor's in computer network engineering Student with 2 years of experience as a Desktop Support Technician at Renton Technical College, providing maintenance and support for PCs, laptops, and bilingual Customer Service Support fluent in English and Spanish.

Skills:

Windows Server 2008, 2012 R2, 2016 | Windows XP, 7, 8, 8.1, 10 | Mac OSX | Linux Ubuntu, Mint, Fedora, Red hat, OpenSUSE | Microsoft Office Suite | Adobe Creative Suite | Cisco Routers | Cisco managed Switches | Wireless | Active Directory | Group Policy | Physical and Software Security | TCP/IP | UDP | DNS | WINS | DHCP | Palo Alto Firewall | Watch Guard | Firewalls | Sophos | Access Control and identity Management | Cryptography | Data Defenses | Routing and Switching | Spanning tree configuration | Printing | Webmin | OSI Model | WDS /Network installs / PXE boot | DFS Troubleshooting | LAN/WAN setup | Virtualization (Hyper-V, VMware, Azure. AWS Amazon Web Services) | Cisco | Hardware / Software repair-replace | Server Rack out | WSUS | Remote support. (TeamViewer, RDP) | Subnetting IPv4, IPv6 | PowerShell | Linux Command Line | Boot Configuration | Linux user and Group Management SharePoint | Data Backup and Recovery | WordPress | Jira ticketing system | GitHub| Docker | Kubernetes | LAMP| NGINX | SQL | Bash | Python.

TestOut Certification:

Renton Technical College, Renton, WA 98056

2017-2018

Routing and Switching Pro (CCNA Equivalent) | Server Pro 2016: Install and Storage (CompTIA Network+ Equivalent) | Linux Pro (CompTIA Linux+ Equivalent) | Security Pro (CompTIA Security+ Equivalent)

Education:

Renton Technical College, Renton WA

3 ,	
 Current student of the Bachelor of Computer Network Engineering 	2020-2022
• Cumulative GPA 3.83	
 Associate of Applied Science in Computer Network Technology 	2018-2019
Graduate of Lindbergh High School, Renton WA	2014-2017
Work Experience	

Work Experience:

Desktop Support Technician

Renton Technical College

2019-Current

- Technical Support in person, via phone and remotely for student owned computers from different vendors, models, and OS.
- Resolve issues relative towards network connectivity, Office 365, hardware, operating system (Win 7/8/10, Mac OS and Linux).
- Deploy new Windows images using windows Deployment Service (WDS) of 8 devices.

- Diagnosed software issues, installed updates or new software, remove malicious program, Data Backup and Recovery Solution
- Break down systems, remove malfunctioning hardware, and install new parts.
- Ordering OEM parts and vendor relationship management
- Printer installation and troubleshooting
- Offer timely technical support and teach users how to utilize computers correctly.
- Python and SQL tutor for Renton Technical college student for lab purpose.

Volunteer Experience:

Renton Park Elementary School 16828 128th Ave Se, Renton, WA 98058

2017-2017

Teacher Aide